先生
次回予告
A processing device?
演算装置
It uses the AIM diffusion field as a medium to build a network.
あれはAIM拡散力場を媒介としてネットワークを構築し
By splitting the processing to multiple brains,
複数の脳に処理を割り振ることで
it makes advanced processing possible.
高度な演算を可能とする
That's the true form of Level Upper.
＜Level Upper>
それが「幻想御手」の正体だよ
Why?
どうして
I asked to use Tree Diagram for a certain simulation,
あるシュミレーションを行うために
<Tree Diagram>
樹形図の設計者の使用申請をしたんだが
but, for some reason, my request was denied.
どういうわけが却下されてね
I needed an alternative processing device.
代わりになる演算装置が必要だった
You're using ability users for something like that?
そんな事のために能力者を
I've gathered around 10,000.
一万人ほど集まった 十分代用してくれるはずだ
As an alternative, it should be more than enough.
Don't look at me like that.
そんな怖い顔をしないでくれ
Everything will be over soon.
もうすぐ全てが終わり
Then will I release everyone.
そうすればみんな解放する
This is a treatment program that will uninstall Level Upper.
幻想御手をアンインストールする治療用プログラムだ
I'll leave it with you.
君に預ける
There are no lasting effects;
everyone will return to the way they were.
後遺症はない
すべて元に戻り 誰も犠牲にはならない
No one will be sacrificed.
I can't trust you.
信用できません
Even if you say that, it hasn't been clinically tested to be safe.
臨床研究が充分でない物を安全だと言われても
It doesn't even make you feel secure!
気休めにもならないじゃないですか
You sure are harsh.
手厳しいな
AIM Analytic Research Center
There are no signs of Kiyama Harumi.
はい　木山春生の姿はありません
Understood. Confiscating data.
了解 データを押収します
Huh? What is this?
何だ　これは
She tricked us!
やられた
They've already broken in.
もう踏み込まれたのか
They're moving too quickly, considering the fact that they only started after they lost communication with you.
君との連絡が途絶えてから動き出したにしては 早すぎるな
They must have deduced it was me by some other way.
別ルートで辿り着いたか
The equipment was programmed to start up the security system if it was accessed without using the necessary procedures.
所定の手続きを踏まずに機材を起動させると
セキュリティが作動するようにプログラムしてあった
Now all data on Level Upper has been lost.
これで幻想御手に関するデータはすべて失われた
The only thing that can awaken the Level Upper users is what you have there.
その使用者を起こせるんのはもう
君が持つそれだけだ
Take good care of it.
大切にしたまえ
You must be Kiyama Harumi!
木山春生だな
Antiskills, hmm?
<Antiskill>
警备员か
They're only quick when they get orders from above.
上から命令があったときだけは 動きの早い奴らだな
You are being arrested on charges of distributing Level Upper.
幻想御手を頒布の被疑者として拘留する
Get out of the car, immediately.
直ちに降車せよ
What are you going to do now?
どうするんです
It looks like it's all over for you.
年貢の納め時みたいですよ
Level Upper is a program designed to make a processing device out of human brains.
幻想御手は
人間の脳を使った演算機器を作るためのプログラムだ
However, it also has an interesting side effect for the user.
だが同時に　使用者にある副産物を齎してくれるんだよ
Let me show you something interesting...
面白い物を見せてやろう
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
未来さえ置き去りにして
限界など知らない　意味無い！
この能力が光散らす　その先に遥かな想いを
チカラ
歩いてきた　この道を　振り返ることしか
出来ないなら…今ここで全てを壊せる
暗闇に堕ちる街並み
人はどこまで立ち向かえるの？
加速するその痛みから
誰かをきっと守れるよ
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 今すぐ
身体中を　光の速さで　駆け巡った　確かな予感
掴め！望むものなら残さず　輝ける自分らしさで
信じてるよ　あの日の誓いを
この瞳に光る涙　それさえも強さになるから
Put both hands behind your head and lie down on the ground!
両手は頭の後ろに組んで
その場でうつぶせになれ
The female hostage is unharmed.
人質の少女は無事です
Uh huh.
Capture her!
確保じゃん
What the hell are you do-
貴様　一体何を
N-No, I didn't mean to do that!
違う　俺の意志じゃない
No way!
馬鹿な　能力者だと
She's an ability user?!
Keep the change!
おつりはいいわ
Get out of here immediately!
早くここから逃げてください
Oh, ma'am!
お客さん
Kuroko, what's the situation like?
黒子　どうなってるの
Kuroko?
黒子
Kiyama is fighting with the Antiskills!
木山が警備員と交戦してますの
And she's even using abilities!
それも　能力を使って
She's an ability user?
彼女　能力者だったの
According to the bank, there is no data stating that Kiyama had any ability development.
<bank>
「書庫」には　木山が能力開発を受けたという記録はないわ
However...
でも
this is obviously an ability.
これは明らかに能力だわ
It also looks as if she is using more than one ability.
それも　複数の能力を使っているとしか
No way...
そんな
The basic rule is that one person has only one ability.
能力は一人に一つだけ　例外はないはずでしょう
There just can't be any exceptions!
Could it be that she's using Level Upper?
幻想御手ではないでしょうか
Huh?
A system where ten thousand ability users are connected through a synaptic network.
一万人もの能力者をネットワークという名のシナプスで繋いだあのシステムは
You could call it a huge brain.
言わば「一つの強大な脳」
If she could control that, she could do things
that would impossible for just one human brain.
もしそれを操れるのなら
人間の脳では有り得ない事も起こし得ますの
If this hypothesis is correct,
この推測は正しいなら
Kiyama is now...
今の木山は
a dreamlike existence. It would be impossible for her to be like this by herself.
実現不可能と言われた幻いの存在
She is a "Dual-Skill". A multiple ability user!
「多重能力者」　デュアルスキルですわ
The Antiskills were completely annihilated?
警備員が　全滅
Uiharu-san!
初春さん
Get yourself together!
しっかりして
Do not worry.
安心しろ
She only lost consciousness from the after-effects of the battle.
戦闘の余波を受けて気絶してるだけだ
She will survive.
命に別状はない
Misaka Mikoto,
御坂美琴
One out of the seven Level Fives in Academy City.
<Level 5>
学園都市に七人しかいない　超能力者
Not even you have fought with someone like me before.
さすがの君も
私のような相手と戦った事はあるまい
Can you stop me, the master of 10,000 brains?
君に　一万の脳を統べる私を止められるかな
Can you stop me, you ask?
止められるかな　ですって
Of course!
当たり前でしょ！
I'm surprised!
驚いたわ
You really can use multiple abilities.
本当にいくつも能力が使えるのね
So you're a "Dual-Skills"? This should be fun.
<Dualskill>　　　
「多重能力者」だなんて
楽しませてくれるじゃない
My ability is actually different from that.
Theoretically, it should be impossible to do what I'm doing.
私の能力は理論上不可能とされるあれとは方式が違う
It's more like... "Multi-Skills".
<Multiskill>
言わば　「多才能力者」だ
Call it whatever you want!
呼び方なんてどうでもいいわよ
It has nothing to do with what I have to do!
こっちがやる事に変わりはないんだから
What's the matter?
どうした
Did you assume that I couldn't use multiple skills at once?
複数の能力を同時に使う事はできないと踏んでいたのかね
Wha-
What is she? She uses abilities without any
concern of getting herself caught in the middle.
なんて奴
自分の巻き込むのもお構いなしに能力を振るってくる
I'm disappointed. Are Level Fives only this powerful?
拍子抜けだな　超能力者というのはこの程度の物なのか
Don't think you've won by defeating a few electric shocks!
電撃を攻略したぐらいで
勝ったと思うな
Huh?
Shi-
しまっ
Shouldn't we end this now?
もう止めにしないか
I only wanted to research something.
あたしはある事柄についた調べたいだけなんだ
After it's finished, I will release everyone.
それが終われば　全員解放する
I won't sacrifice anyone.
誰も犠牲にはしない
Quit joking!
ふざけんじゃないわよ
You won't sacrifice anyone, you say?
誰も犠牲にしない
After getting all those people involved...
あれだけの人間を巻き込んでおいて
and playing with people's feelings like that.
人の心を弄んでおいて
How can I ignore it?!
そんな物　見過ごせるわけないでしょうか
Even though you are a Level Five,
超能力者とは言え
you still are just some ojousama who
doesn't even know how society works.
所詮は世間知らずのお嬢様か
I really don't want to hear that from somebody like you!
あんたにだけは言われたくないわ
The ability development you undergo every day, do you think it's humane and safe?
君達が日常的に受けている能力開発
あれが安全で人道的な物だとでも思っているのか
The higher-ups in Academy City are hiding something important about abilities.
学園都市の上層部は能力に関する重大な何かを隠している
Without knowing that, the teachers in this city are "developing" the brains of students every day.
それを知らずにこの町の教師達は　学生の脳を日々開発してるんだ
You should know how dangerous that is.
それがどんなに危険なことかわかるだろう
That sounds like an interesting argument.
なかなか面白そうな話じゃない
I'll have plenty of time to investigate that after capturing you!
あんたを捕まえた後でゆっくりと　調べさせてもらうわ
I'm sorry but I can't be captured yet!
残念だが　まだ捕まるわけにはいかない
Cans?
空き缶
Graviton!
<Graviton>
虛空爆破
So, what will you do now?
さあ　どうする
I'll blast them all!
全部　吹っ飛ばす
Amazing.
凄いな
However...
だが
So... how was that? That's how I'd do it!
どう　ざっとこんなもんよ
Are you finished yet-
もうお仕舞いな
I thought I would get more trouble out of you.
もっと手こずるかと思ったが
But I guess Level Fives are only this good.
こんな物か　超能力者
I don't mind if you hate me.
恨んでもらって構わんよ
Gotcha!
捕まえた
No way...
馬鹿な
You built a makeshift shield with magnetic forces?
磁力で即席の盾を組上げたのか
Close contact electric shock...
零距離からの電撃
It didn't work on that bastard before, but you don't have an absurd ability like that, do you?
あの馬鹿には効かなかったけど
いくらなんでもあんなとんでも能力までは持ってないわよね
Too slow!
遅い
I did try to limit myself, you know...
一応手加減はしといたから
Sensei!
先生　先生
What is this?
何
Sensei!
It's coming directly from my head.
頭の中に直接
Sensei!
先生　先生
Are these Kiyama Harumi's memories?
これは　木山春生の記憶
Sensei!
A circuit was created between Kiyama and me using electricity as a medium.
私と木山の間に電気を介した回線が繋がって
Sensei!
先生
木山
老师
A Certain Scientific Railgun
Kiyama
Sensei
Kiyama Sensei!
木山先生
I'm going to be a teacher?
私が教師に
Is this some joke?
何かの冗談ですか
Oh, no.
いやいや　君は教員免許を持っていたよね
You have a teacher's license, right?
Yes.
ええ
Then there's nothing strange about you being a teacher.
なら　教鞭を取っても　何もおかしくはないじゃないか
But I only took that because I had the chance.
しかし　あれはついでに取っただけで
I'm not telling you to go away from research.
研究から離れろと言っているわけではないんよ
Quite the opposite.
それどころか
I'm thinking of putting you in charge of an experiment initiated by the Administration Committee.
統括理事会肝入りの実験を任せたいと思っているんだ
Seriously?
本当ですか
Those kids...
あの子供達
They are called "Child Errors".
<Child Error>
彼らは「置き去り」と言ってね
They are orphan children who were thrown away into Academy City for one reason or another.
何らかの事情で学園都市に捨てられた 身寄りのない子供達だ
I see.
They will be the test subjects of this experiment...
そして　今回の実験の被験者であり
and the students you will be in charge of.
君が担当する生徒になる
Huh?
To successfully complete the experiment,
実験を成功させるには被験者の詳細な成長データを取り
we will have to collect detailed growth data on the test subjects...
and prepare it with the utmost attention to detail.
細心の注意を払って調整を行う必要がある
To do this, it's more effective for you to become their teacher.
だったら　担任として受け持った方が手間が省けるでしょ
That might be true but...
それは　そうかもしれませんが
Future Education Department
Child Ability Development Center
Attached Elementary School
Kiyama Harumi
Err...
あー　今日から君達の担任になった　木山春生だ
I'm Kiyama Harumi. Starting today, I am going to be your teacher.
Nice to meet you.
よろしく
Nice to meet you!
よろしくお願いします
It's become a troublesome situation for me.
厄介なことになった
Hey! You fell for it!
引っかかった
You fell for it!
引っかかった　引っかかった
Hey you!
コラ
Sensei, are you all right?
先生　大丈夫
Yeah.
Since it's sunny, they'll dry in a moment if I hang them out.
晴れてる事だし　干しておけばすぐに乾く
Don't undress here!
こんなとこで着替えないで
Boys! Look the other way!
男子　あっち向いてろ
No, Sensei! You're a girl!
駄目だよ　先生
It's boring looking at Sensei's small boobs!
べ　別に先生のペチャパイ見てもしょーがねーよな
Hurry up and get dressed, please!
Y-Yeah...
Hurry up.
Small breasts?
ぺ　ペチャ
I hate children.
子供は嫌いだ
They have no delicacy.
デリカシーがない
You aren't very popular, are you?
先生ってもてねーだろ 彼氏いんの
Do you have a boy friend?
W-What are you asking?
な　何を
I'll be your boyfriend if you want me to.
何なら 俺が付き合ってやろうか
They're rude.
失礼だし
And as you can see...
そして　このように
They do pranks.
悪戯するし
What's the matter?
どうしたんだ
If something is troubling you, you can tell Sensei...
何が困ったことがあるのなら　先生に
They aren't logical.
論理的じゃないし
Oh, you can't just eat only stuff you like!
好き嫌いしちゃ駄目なんだよ
Eh... oh...
They are inconsiderate.
なれなれしいし　すぐに懐いてくる
And try to become friendly too quickly.
I hate children.
子供は嫌いだ
Ouch...
Huh?
What's the matter, Edasaki?
どうした　枝先
Oh, Kiyama-Sensei.
木山先生
I slipped and fell.
滑って転んちゃった
My apartment is close by.
私のマンションはすぐそこだが
You want to take a bath?
風呂を貸そうか
Can I?!
いいの
Wow, it's a bath!
お風呂だ
Does having a bath really make you that happy?
風呂がそんなにうれしいか
Yes!
うちの施設 週二回のシャワーだけだもん
Since we only get a shower twice a week at our facility.
Can I really go in?
本当に入っていいの
Sure.
ああ
Yahoo!
やった　みんなに自慢しちゃおと
I can brag to everyone!
Sensei...
先生
Huh?
Will I be able to become Level 4 or 5 if I try hard?
私でも　頑張ったら大能者とか超能者になれるかな
I can't really say anything at this point.
今の段階では何とも言えないな
Do you have some admiration for high level ability users?
高レベルの能力者に憧れがあるのか
Hmm... That also, but...
んーもちろんそれもあるけど
Since Academy City is raising us,
私たちは学園都市に育ててもらってるから
I'd like to become useful to the city.
この街の役に立てるようになりたいなーって
I really have no time for research now.
研究の時間がなくなってしまった
This sure is a lot of trouble.
本当にいい迷惑だ
Children... I hate them.
子供は　嫌い　だ
They are noisy and have no delicacy.
騒がしいし デリカシーがない
Hey, be my girlfriend.
ねね　俺の彼女になれんなよ
Yeah, right.
はいはい
They're rude.
失礼だし
They do pranks.
悪戯するし
Is that me?
私
Yep.
They aren't logical.
論理的じゃないし
Happy Birthday
Happy birthday, Sensei!
先生　お誕生日　おめでとう
Happy Birthday
Happy birthday, Sensei!
先生　おめでとう
Choosing what you like and don't like to eat...
好き嫌いは
Right, I wasn't supposed to do that.
しちゃだめだったな
So Sensei can do it when she should!
先生　やればできるじゃん
先生えらい
Children...
子供は
This will sting a bit.
チクッとするよ
No anomalies with the numbers?
数値に異常はないか
All fine here.
こちらは問題ありません
Fine here too.
こちらも大丈夫です
Understood.
良し　分かった
Are you scared?
怖くないか
Not at all.
全然
Since it’s Kiyama-Sensei's research, right?
だって　木山先生の実験なんでしょう
I believe in you.
先生のこと信じてるもん
Now this teacher-play-acting is finished.
これで先生ごっこもおしまいか
Dopamine levels decreasing!
ドーパミン値低下中
Anti-Choline medication is ineffective!
抗コリン剤の効果　ありません
Large scale thermal injuries are causing hypovolemic shock!
広範囲熱傷による低容量性ショックが
Administer Ringer's Solution!
乳酸からリンゲル液輸液急げ
Start blood transfusions!
It's impossible!
無理です　これ以上は
We can't go any further!
Contact hospitals immediately!
早く病院に連絡を
Oh, there's no need for that.
いいからいいから
But at this rate...
しかし　このままでは
Don't be so surprised. Collect data properly.
浮足立ってないで　データをちゃんと集めなさい
We will be ordering silence about this experiment throughout the facility.
この実験については所内に緘口令を布く
This experiment has been completed without incident.
実験は恙無く終了した
You all saw nothing, right?
君達は何も見なかった
いいね
S-Sure.
はい
Kiyama-kun, well done.
木山君　よくやってくれた
I'm sorry for them.
彼らには気の毒だな
However, it was necessary, for the evolution of science.
科学の発展には付き物だよ
Don't worry about this mishap.
今回の事故は気にしなくていい
I still expect great things from you.
君には今後も期待しているからね
What was that...
今のは
You saw it?
見られた　のかっ
The road disappeared?
道がなくなってる
Misaka-san?!
御坂さん
Why?
何で　何であんな事
Why did something like that...
That was publicly considered an experiment for controlling AIM diffusion field.
あれは表向きAIM拡散力場を制御するための実験とされていた
But in reality, it was a controlled explosion to analyze the laws of out-of-control abilities.
が　実際は暴走能力の法則解析用誘爆実験だ
The real purpose was to stimulate the AIM diffusion field and to understand the conditions of going "out-of-control".
AIM拡散力場を刺激して
暴走の条件は知るのが本当の目的だったというわけさ
Then...
じゃ
They were intended to go out-of-control...
暴走は意図的に仕組まれていたのさ
I only realized that much later.
もっとも　気づいたのは後になってからだがね
Human testing...
人体　実験
Those children never woke up; they still are asleep!
あの子達は　一度も目覚めることなく
いまなお眠り続けている
We used them as disposable guinea pigs!
私たちは　あの子達を使い捨てのモルモットにしたんだ
But...
でも　そんな事があったんなら　警备員に通報して
If something like that happened, you could have contacted the Antiskills-
23 times...
２３回
In order to seek recovery of those children...
あの子達の恢復手段を探るため
and to create simulations to understand why the accident happened,
そして事故の原因を究明するシミュレーションを行うために
that's the number of times I asked for use of the Tree Diagram.
<Tree Diagram>
「樹形図の設計者」の使用を申請した回数だ
If I could use the processing ability of the Tree Diagram,
<Tree Diagram>
「樹形図の設計者」の演算能力を持ってすれば
I would be able to save them.
あの子達を助けられるはずだった
I would be able to let them run out under the sun once more!
もう一度太陽の下を走らせてやることもできただろう
Yet they declined all 23 times!
だが　却下された
２３回ともすべて
Huh?
The Administrative Committee is behind it! There's no way the Antiskills would budge!
統括理事会がグルなんだ
警備員が動くわけがない
Even still, your current method is-
だからって　こんなやり方
What would you know?
君に何が分かる？！
I will do anything to save those children.
あの子達を救うためなら
私は何だってする
Even if it involves making this
entire city my enemy, I won't stop!
この街の全てを敵に回しても　止めるわけにはいかないんだ
Hey...
ちょっと
The Network is going out of control?!
ネットワークの暴走　これは
This is...
What is that?
何　あれ
A fetus?
胎児？
待
续
A Certain Scientific Railgun
To be continued
待
续
Dear My Friend Every day & night
Always be with you
Dear My Friend every day & night
話しても　まだまだ　足りないまま
夕焼けが　街を染めてゆく
思うように　なかなか　いかない…って
気づいたら　一緒に　泣いていた
恋も　夢も　花も　虹も　風も
ぜんぶ掴もうよ
ダイジョウブ！　元気出して
私がそばにいるから
今日のミス　悔やむより　今　乗り越えて
ダイジョウブ！　迷わないで
まだ見ぬ未来へと向かって
ずっと　歩いてゆこう
Dear My Friend every day & night
Always be with you
Next Episode
I will break Kiyama's ambitions!
木山の野望は私が挫く
AIM
Burst
幻想猛兽
And I will save Saten-san!
佐天さんは私が助けてみせる
って　何を　この化け物
Hey! What is this monster?!
怪獣を相手だなんて　聞いてないんわよ
I was never told I'd be facing monsters!